Guide to the Edith Altschul Lehman Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Edith Altschul Lehman Papers,
1856-1976 [
Bulk Dates: 1963-1976].
Lehman, Herbert H., Mrs.
17 linear ft. ( 27 document boxes; 1 record carton; 2 file card boxes; 4 oversize boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#0762
4078517
This collection documents the life of Edith Altschul Lehman, a philanthropist who supported many social projects in New York City. Edith Lehman was the wife of New York Governor and Senator Herbert H. Lehman.
Biographical Note
Edith Louise Altschul was born in San Francisco on August 8, 1889 to Charles and Camilla Altschul. Charles, a successful banker with Lazard Freres, moved the family to New York City in 1901. Edith attended Dr. Sach's Girls School and Miss Jacoby's School (now the Calhoun School) and took a nursing course after graduation. She met Herbert H. Lehman, a partner in the Lehman Brothers investment firm, at a picnic. They were married on April 28, 1910 and would have three children, Peter, John, and Hilda.
Edith considered her marriage her career and the most important aspect of her life, but she was also deeply involved in social welfare and philanthropy. She organized a social service committee to care for the family needs of hospitalized patients. This endeavor led to the creation of Mount Sinai Hospital's first professional social service department, and she remained closely associated with the hospital for many years thereafter.
Lehman was also involved with the Henry Street Settlement, which provided health care and other assistance to new immigrants and the poor living in the Lower East Side of New York City. In 1948 the Lehman's built Pete's House, a youth center at Henry Street Settlement dedicated to the memory of their son Peter, who was killed in World War II. Peter had volunteered as a youth leader at the Settlement.
In 1917, Edith Lehman became a charter member of the Play Schools Association, which promoted play as vital to the mental and physical health of children. The organization partnered with schools, hospitals, and other institutions to provide opportunities for creative play. Lehman would work with the organization for over fifty years, serving as president and as Chairman of the Board from 1966 until her death in 1976.
Edith Lehman was also involved in the Jewish communities of New York and a member of the American Jewish Committee and the Federation of Jewish Philanthropies, among other organizations. She was a supporter of Israel, and first visited the country in 1949 with her husband. The Edith Lehman High School in Dimona, Israel, was dedicated to her.
In 1961, the Lehman's built the Lehman Children's Zoo (now the Tisch Zoo) in New York City's Central Park in honor of their 50th wedding anniversary. Although the zoo was renovated in 1997, the bronze Lehman Gates still stand at the entrance.
After her husband's death in 1963, Edith Lehman established several major endowments and institutions in his honor, including contributions to Mount Sinai Hospital Medical School and the establishment of the Lehman Professorship in Pediatrics at that institution; the Lehman Educational Fund, which offers scholarships for African American college students; and the Lehman School of Ethics at the Jewish Theological Seminary. She also supported Williams College, Herbert Lehman's alma mater, and financed and endowed the Lehman Suite at Columbia University's School of International and Political Affairs.
In recognition for her dedication to social causes, Edith Lehman was awarded honorary doctor of humane letters degrees from Williams College and Mount Sinai School of Medicine, as well as a doctor of laws from Columbia University.
Edith Altschul Lehman died on March 8, 1976, in New York City.
Scope and Content
This collection documents the life of Edith Altschul Lehman, a philanthropist and the wife of New York Governor and Senator Herbert H. Lehman. It supplements files on Edith Lehman which had been integrated into the Herbert H. Lehman Papers (MS#0763). The majority of materials relate to Edith Lehman's philanthropic activities, such as the construction of the Lehman Children's Zoo, contributions to the Henry Street Settlement, and her involvement in numerous organizations including the Play Schools Association, the American Jewish Committee, and the Federation of Jewish Philanthropies. Other material concerns her marriage to Herbert Lehman and her family life. The collection is comprised of correspondence, diaries, notebooks, speeches, photographs, audiotapes, and memorabilia.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into three series:
Series I: Subject Files, 1942-1976
Series III: Condolences, 1976
Series III: Memorabilia, 1856-1989
Subjects
Henry Street Settlement (New York, N.Y.); American Jewish Committee.; Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York.; Herbert H. Lehman Collections (Columbia University); Play Schools Association.; Lehman, Edith A. (Edith Altschul).--local; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Central Park (New York, N.Y.); Central Park Children's Zoo (New York, N.Y.); New York (State)--Politics and government--1951-; Women--Diaries.; Social settlements--New York (State)--New York.; Zoos--New York (State)--New York.; Children's zoos--New York (State)--New York.; Jews--New York (State)--New York--Societies, etc.; Jews--Charities.; Governors' spouses--New York (State); Humanitarianism.; Photoprints.; Diaries.; Women philanthropists.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room. This collection has no restrictions.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Correspondence, diaries, notebooks, speeches, photographs, tape recordings, memorabilia bequest Lehman, Edith Altschul
Bequest of Edith Altschul Lehman, 1977.
Related Material
Edith Lehman materials from 1910 to 1962 are integrated into the Herbert H. Lehman Papers, Herbert H. Lehman Suite and Papers, Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
Herbert H. Lehman Papers, Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University
Frank Altschul Papers, Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University
Finding Aid available in repository and online; folder level control.
Online finding aid available.
- Series I: Subject Files, 1942-1976
  The majority of the subject files document Edith Lehman's social and philanthropic activities. Files relating to the Play Schools Association reflect her role as president and chairman and include correspondence, reports, memos, and conference materials. Sponsorship files contain brief notes recording her responses to event invitations and to the many requests for her sponsorship or endorsement of particular groups. Other files focus on particular projects, organizations, and individuals and contain correspondence and memos. Files are arranged alphabetically.
  - A, 1963-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abortion Law Repeal Legislation, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abrams, Morris B., 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Altschul, Frank and Helen G., 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Altschul, Frank and Helen G.--80th Birthday Party, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Council for Judaism, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Friends of Hebrew University, 1964-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1964-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Animal Legislation, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Animal Shipment Legislation, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arnstein, Mr. and Mrs. Lawrence, 1965-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General, 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - B, 1964-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Beame, Abraham, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Benton, William and Helen, 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bingham, Jonathon B. and June R., 1964-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Birmingham, Stephen--"Our Crowd," 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - B'nai B'rith Lehman Exhibition (Washington), 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bragdon, Paul E., 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brandeis University, 1964-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brunkard, Thomas V. Memorial Service, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - C, 1956-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Carey, Hugh L., 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Carey Transition Council, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Children's Zoo, 1961-1976, (3 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 4 to 6)
  - Columbia University, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Constitutional Convention, New York State, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cordier, Andrew W. 1969-1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Council for Livestock Protection, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Crank Letters, 1966-1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - D, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dimona, Israel, Edith Lehman High School, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Douglas, Paul H. and Emily, 1966-1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - E, 1964-1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Edelstein, Julius C.C., 1966-1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - F, 1964-1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies, 1966-1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Friends of Central Park Zoo, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - G, 1967-1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Goodhart, Arthur L. and Family, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Gore, Albert, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - H, 1964-1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Henry Street Settlement, 1970-1975, (4 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 9 to 12)
  - Henry Street Settlement 1965-1969, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Humane Slaughter of Animals, 1957-1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H. and Muriel, 1960-1976, (3 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 4 to 6)
  - I, 1965-1972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Israel, 1967-1973 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - J, 1964-1974 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Jackson, Barbara, 1964-175 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Jackson, Sir Robert G. A., 1965-1976 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary of America, 1965-1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. and Lady Bird, 1963-1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. Inauguration, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Johnson-Humphrey Campaign 1964 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - K, 1966-1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Kennedy, Robert F., 1960-1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Koch, Edward I., 1964-1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Krents, Harold, 1960-1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - L, 1965-1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Lehman, Edith Altschul
    - Art Exhibition Catalogs, 1954-1961 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - 85th Birthday Party, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - New York Post Interview, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Speeches, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Speeches, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Lehman, Herbert H. College, 1967-1976, (3 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 4 to 6)
  - Lehman, Herbert H.--Juvenile Biography Plans, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Lehman, Mayer--Family Fund, 1969-1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Lehman, Orin 1964-1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Leidesdorf, Samuel D. 1964-1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Lindsey, John V. 1964-1969 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - M, 1968-1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - McGovern Campaign, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Magnes Memorial Museum (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Metropolitan Museum and Central Park, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Mondale, Walter F., 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Morgenthau, Robert--D.A. Campaign, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Morgenthau, Robert--Gubernatorial Campaign, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Mount Sinai Hospital and School of Medicine, 1964-1976 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - N, 1963-1975 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - National--General, 1958-1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - N.A.A.C.P.-- Herbert H. Lehman Education Fund, 1965-1974 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - New York Hospital-- Hilda Master Chair, 1967-1974 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - New York State-- Lehman Memorial Fellowships, 1964-1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - New York State Thruway, 1942-1964 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - New York University Medical Center, 1964-1971 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - O, 1970-1975 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - P, 1965-1974 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Philanthropies, 1968-1975 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Play Schools Association
    - Biennial Conference, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - General, 1974-1976, (6 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 2 to 7)
    - Biennial Conference, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Political--General, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Presidential Medal of Freedom, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - R, 1964-1974 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor--Memorial Foundation, 1964-1972 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.--Monument Committee, 1966-1975 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Sa-Se, 1960-1974 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Sh-Sy, 1964-1974 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Sponsorships, 1966-1975, (10 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 6 to 15)
  - T, 1964-1972 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1962-1975 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - U-V, 169-1975 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - W, 1963-1973 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Wagner, Robert Jr., 1964-1975 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Wald, Lillian D.-- Election to the Hall of Fame, 1965-1971 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Weinfeld, Edward, 1965-1975, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Williams College, 1964-1974 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Williams College--Scholarships, 1960s-1970s (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Wise, Hilda Jane Lehman and Family, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Yale University, 1970-1975 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Y-Z, 1965-1975 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Series II: Condolences, 1976
  This small series holds obituaries, funeral service information, and letters of condolence sent to Edith Lehman's children and family after her death in March 1976.
  - Obituary, 1976 (Box 31)
  - Funeral Service--General, 1976 (Box 31)
  - Condolence Letters--A-Z, 1976, (8 Folders) (Box 31)
  - Condolence Letters--General, 1976 (Box 31)
- Series III: Memorabilia, 1856-1976
  This series holds a variety of notebooks, awards, artifacts, and other objects representing many aspects of Edith Lehman's life. It includes elaborately bound scrapbooks and other gifts from her uncle, Richard Altschul, which he made each year for his niece's birthday. Consisting of family traditions and injokes, they were known as "The Richy Classics." The series also houses family documents, the diaries, and several photo albums documenting wedding anniversaries and trips. Other albums cover events such as the dedication of Herbert Lehman College and the construction of Pete’s House; most of these were given to the Lehman's as commemorative gifts. The series contains a watercolor painting of the Lehman Children's Zoo and two original sketches of the zoo's animal sculptures, designed by artist Aymar Embury. Also included are social books, Christmas gift lists, diplomas and membership certificates, and awards, medals, pins, statues, and other items given to Edith in recognition of her philanthropic activities.
  - Richard Altschul Gifts
    - "Just C & Y"--Book Box with Letter, 1925 (Box 23)
    - "What I know About Social Services" and Letters, 1917 (Box 30)
    - "Infra Red and Ultraviolet Pictures of Family Life in New York, 1924 August 18 (Box 30)
    - "Lest We Forget"--Scrapbook of California made for Charles and Camilla Altschul, 1901 (Box 30)
    - "Cressy's History of California, Edition Grand de Luxe," 1923 (Box 30)
  - Awards and Commemorative Objects
    - Testimonial by Women's Division of the American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee--Guest Signatures, 1936 (Box 19)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People--Certificate of Life Membership for Edith Lehman, 1960 (Box 20)
    - Mount Sinai Plaque, 1955 (Box 20)
    - Judge Irving Lehman--Golden Jubilee Scroll from the National Jewish Welfare Board, April 12, 1967 (Box 20)
    - Jewish Theological Seminary of America--Certificate, 1965-1966 (Box 20)
    - Louise Waterman Wise Award, 1973 (Box 20)
    - Legislative Correspondents Association of the State of New York--Certificate, 1937 (Box 21)
    - "The Deserted Wives in 'A Little Party of Our Own'" --by the Wives of the Legislative Correspondents Association of the State of New York, 1934 (Box 21)
    - For Mrs. Herbert Lehman by the International Ladies Garment Workers' Union--Gold Needle and Thimble, July 1, 1959 (Box 24)
    - American Jewish Committee--Anti-Defamation League--Medal, undated (Box 24)
    - Medical Board of Mount Sinai Hospital--Medal, 1968 (Box 24)
    - For Edith A. Lehman on Her Eightieth Birthday--Medal from the Play Schools Association, August 18, 1969 (Box 24)
    - Felix M. Warburg Memorial Award, undated (Box 24)
    - United Jewish Appeal--Medal Commemorating the 20th Anniversary of V-E Day, 1965 (Box 24)
    - United Jewish Appeal--Medal Commemorating the 50th Anniversary of Karen Hayesod, 1970 (Box 24)
    - Mount Sinai Hospital Trusteeship Medals, 1946 (2 medals) (Box 24)
    - Mount Sinai Hospital Board of Trustees Medal--Brass in Lucite, 1963 (Box 24)
    - Silver Medal Commemorating Dedication of the Eleanor Roosevelt Wing of the Franklin D. Roosevelt Library--Eleanor Roosevelt Memorial Foundation, May 3, 1972 (Box 24)
    - Lifetime Pass to the Central Park Children's Zoo--by the Department of Parks, undated (Box 24)
    - Lifetime Membership in the Woman's Division, Federation of Jewish Philanthropies--Membership Card, 1966 (Box 24)
    - Howard University Centennial Medal in Appreciation of Gift to Alumni Scholarship Fund, 1967 (Box 24)
    - Medal with US Congress Seal from Jonathan Bingham, undated (Box 24)
    - Honorary Membership from New York Chapter of Hadassah, 1961 (Box 25)
    - Brandeis University Plaque in Appreciation of Gift to Library Trust Fund, undated (Box 25)
    - Plaque to Edith Lehman from the Board of Trustees of Brandeis University--Naming Her as Fellow of the University, April 17, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Elected to the Society of Honor Reform Jewish Appeal, 1965-1970--Statues (4 statues) (Box 26)
    - Statue to Herbert Lehman for his 80th Birthday by Honor Reform Jewish Appeal, undated (Box 26)
    - Bust of John Kennedy by Robert Berkes, Presented by 65th Anniversary Convention of the International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, 1965 May (Box 26)
    - Mount Sinai Medical Center Memorial Resolution, 1976 March (Box 27)
    - Naming of Herbert H. Lehman College--Certificate, 1968 (Box 28)
    - Resolution of Appreciation from Henry Street Settlement Urban Life Center--Certificate, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Citation from Americans for Democratic Action at Annual National--Certificate, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Tribute in Honor of Herbert Lehman Presented to Edith Lehman by the Jewish Teachers Seminary and People's University--Certificate, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Election of Edith Lehman to the Society of Honorary Alumni of the Hebrew University of Jerusalem--Certificate, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Dedication of the Edith Lehman Comprehensive High School, Israel--Certificate, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Original lithograph by Chaim Gross from the United Jewish Appeal of Greater New York, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Class Bowl Engraved with "In Appreciation" from Jonathan Bingham, 1972 (Box Lehman Suite cabinet)
    - Blue and White Plate from Thanks to Scandinavia, 1973 (Box Lehman Suite cabinet)
  - Degrees
    - Williams College--Diploma, 1967 (Box 20)
    - National Red Cross--Volunteer Special Services Certificate, 1944 (Box 25)
    - Mount Sinai School of Medicine, Honorary Doctor of Humane Letters--Diploma, 1976 (Box 34)
    - Columbia University, Honorary Doctor of Laws--Diploma and Photographs, 1972 (Box 27)
  - Photo Albums
    - Golden Wedding Anniversary, 1960 (Box 18)
    - Edith Lehman High School in Dimona, Israel--Photo Album, 1965 (Box 19)
    - Visit to Israel--Photo Album, 1959 (Box 19)
    - "ORT" in Israel--Photo Book, undated (Box 20)
    - Governor Lehman and the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America: a Photographic Record Presented to Mrs. Edith Lehman, 1967 October 9 (Box 21)
    - Pete's House--Henry St. Settlement--Photo Book, undated (Box 22)
    - Launching of the Diesel Electric Ferryboat "The Governor Herbert H. Lehman" 1964 September 5 (Box 22)
    - 820 Park Avenue--Tenth Floor, March 1976 (Box 25)
    - 820 Park Avenue--Eleventh Floor, March 1976 (Box 25)
    - Photographs--EAL, 1975 (Box 25)
    - Herbert H. Lehman Village, Israel--Photo Album, 1959 (Box 34)
    - Edith Lehman High School at Dimona, Israel--Plans, undated (Box 27)
    - Meadow Farm, undated (Box 27)
    - Play Schools Association--Book of Photographs and Children's Artwork, 1960 (Box 28)
    - Friends of the Zoo: Teenage Volunteers at the Lehman Children's Zoo--Photo Album, 1975 (Box 28)
    - Dedication of Herbert Lehman College, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Edith Lehman 50th Anniversary Fund, 1917-1968, (2 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Meadow Farm Album, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Mount Sinai School of Medicine--The Investiture of Horace L. Hodes, MD as the First Lehman Professor of Pediatrics, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Naming of Herbert H. Lehman College, 1967 (Box 30)
    - Teenage Photograph Workshop, Henry Street Settlement, 1957 (2 binders) (Box 33)
    - Dedication of the Herbert H. Lehman Suite, Columbia University, 1971 (Box 33)
    - Hubert H and Muriel Humphrey--Framed Photograph, undated (Box Lehman Suite cabinet)
  - General
    - Political Contributions, 1964-1976 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - European Trip Notebook, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Birthday List, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Memory Book, 1957-1975 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Gift List, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Tipping Memory Book, 1926-1972 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Christmas, 1956-1974, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Edith Altschul Lehman--Diary, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Elisabeth Josephson Altschul--Diary, 1856-1872 (3 copies) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Social Books
      - Social Book1950-1956 (Box 17)
      - Social Book, 1957-1963 (Box 17)
      - Social Book, 1966-1970 (Box 17)
      - Beverage Preferences, 1968 (Box 17)
      - Social Book, 1971-1974 (Box 18)
      - Social Book, 1975 (Box 18)
    - Engagement Calendar, 1976 (Box 18)
    - The Book of the Bride Elect Designed by a Spinster--Wedding Gifts, 1910 (Box 18)
    - Family Trees--Lehman and Altschul, 1974 (Box 18)
    - S.S. Commodore--Passenger List, 1909 April 4 (Box 18)
    - Lehman Village--General Information, Israel, 1959 (Box 19)
    - "The Josephson Family"--History by Gertrude Furth, undated (Box 22)
    - Matchbook with Picture of Herbert and Edith Lehman, undated (Box 25)
    - Herbert and Edith Lehman Bookplates, undated (Box 25)
    - Menu, 1910 April 28 (Box 25)
    - Genealogy Notes--Index Cards, undated (Box 25)
    - Pencil Sketches of the Whale and the Rabbit Sculptures for the Lehman Children's Zoo by Artist Aymar Embury, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Watercolor Sketch of Children's Zoo by C. Weiss, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Dead Sea Scrolls Replica, undated (Box 30)
    - Israel Diary, 1959, (2 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Children's Zoo Illustration on the cover of The New Yorker, 1964 January 25 (Box Lehman Suite Cabinet)